Resume

Name: Sujit Kumar

Contact: (+91) 7517213155

E-Mail ID: sujitkumar.kr00@gmail.com

Summary

4.6 Years experience as Software Engineer with expertise in front-end and back-end development, Experienced in PHP developer(4.6+ years) and React Js.

Skills

Programming Languages: PHP | JavaScript | 00PS **Web Technologies:** HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap

Third Party API Integration: Payment Gateway(**Stripe**, **Razorpay**)

Libraries/Frameworks: Laravel | CodeIgniter | Ajax | Jquery | React js | Redux

Databases/Tools: MySQL | GitHub | GitLab

Work Experience

Tavant Technologies | Software Engineer | FullStack developer(PHP)

Jan 2022 - Present | Bangalore

- Write clean, efficient, and maintainable **PHP** code.
- Develop server-side logic to handle requests and responses
- Build dynamic and responsive websites using PHP frameworks in **Laravel** and **CodeIgniter**.
- Optimized database queries in MySQL to improve overall database performance by 43%.
- Develop **RESTful APIs** to connect backend systems with front-end interfaces
- Integrated third-party APIs (payment gateways, social media APIs, or email services).
- Troubleshooting and debugging applications to resolve issues and enhance performance.
- Implement security best practices to protect applications from vulnerabilities like **SQL injection**, XSS, and **CSRF**.
- Use secure authentication mechanisms like **OAuth**, **JWT**, or session management.
- Developed and maintained user interfaces using **React.js**, resulting in a 30% reduction in development time for new projects.
- Utilized **React-Redux** for state management, resulting in a 25% reduction in code complexity and a 15% increase in team productivity
- Design, develop, and maintain efficient, reusable, and reliable React components.
- Ensure web applications are **mobile-friendly** and **responsive** using CSS frameworks like **Tailwind CSS**, Bootstrap, or custom CSS.
- Improved 30% page load speed by optimizing code and reducing unnecessary requests using **React js**.

Ample Softech Systems | PHP Developer

July 2020 - Sep 2021 | Pune

- Designed and implemented dynamic websites and web applications using PHP and Laravel..
- Created Authentication and Authorization in **PHP using JWT**.
- Monitored application performance and resolved technical issues to minimize downtime.
- Optimized database queries, reducing page load times by 40%.

Skylex Technologies | Jr. Software Developer

Sep 2019 - May 2020 | Pune

- Write clean, efficient, and reusable code in core PHP
- Code maintenance and enhancement.
- Integration of user-facing elements developed by front-end developers.

Educational Details

- B.E in EEE, from AVIT College, Chennai, Vinayaka Mission University (TN) 2016 with 74%
- 12th from R.L.S.Y College Bettiah, B.S.E.B Patna in 2011 with 72.6%.
- 10th from Raj High School Bettiah, B.S.E.B Patna in 2009 with 70.2%.

Project Work

Project 1: Car-Rental

Environment/Platform: PHP(Laravel) | MySQL | React Js | HTML | CSS | BootStrap

Description: Created this project to provide more flexibility in car rental business so it help to reduce staff business time while also reducing 90% manual workload.it is also help to customer to save time and money and provide flexibility.so this software increase 40% of customer engagement

Project 2: Simna Properties

Environment/Platform: PHP(Laravel) | React js | MySQL | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | BootStrap

Description: Created this real estate software to automates the manual activities and decreases the paperwork. It help to client with extensive market research, which lead to higher engagement and conversion rates of 30%.

Project 3: School ERP

Environment/Platform: PHP(CodeIgniter) | **MySQL** | JavaScript | Ajax | Jquery | JSON | HTML | CSS | **BootStrap**

Description: Developed this school ERP to reduce 90% manual work of management team and Increased productivity exhibited by teachers, staff, and students. saved time and resources due to the automation of core school operations so increase 20% revenue of business.it established Seamless communication between parents, students, and teachers.

Personal Details

Name: Sujit kumar Gender: Male

Marital Status: Married

Address: Koramangala, Bangalore-560034

Languages Known: English, Hindi.

Declaration: I here by declare that the information mentioned above is true to the best of my Knowledge.

Sujit Kumar